<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Walzr</title>
    <link>https://walzr.com/</link>
    <description>All posts from walzr.com auto-generated into RSS</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 13:33:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>New project</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/new-project</link>
      <description>Routeshuffle, launching early next year, is a new website for generating random running, biking, and walking routes. Unlike competitors, Routeshuffle will feature modern design and essential functionalities like sign-in and exporting to Google Maps. Built using Node.js, Express, Sendgrid, and Stripe on a Chromebook, this project aims to make it easier for users to get outside and exercise. Stay tuned for updates!</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:34:48 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Touring Google</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/touring-google</link>
      <description>After winning Mentor Foundation USA's "Living the Example" contest aimed at preventing youth drug usage, I embarked on an exciting trip to Los Angeles. A highlight was touring Google's Venice Beach offices with Gudrun Giddings, CEO of G4C Innovation and board member of Mentor Foundation USA. The tour showcased Google's innovative workspaces, employee perks, and healthy dining options. Next, we visited the YouTube Space in La Playa, learning about its resources for content creators. The day concluded with a delightful meal at The Fat Dog in West Hollywood, making this trip truly memorable.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:34:42 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bump</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/bump</link>
      <description>As a high school runner, indoor track meets in winter present unique challenges, including poor air quality and cramped tracks. The frustration builds as spectators carelessly cross the track mid-race, evoking 'Run Rage,' a fierce determination to win despite anger at the conditions and interruptions. This intensity isn't limited to indoor events; similar frustrations occur in cross country races. These experiences reveal a version of myself that becomes indifferent to everything except finishing the race strong.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:34:40 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WWDC scholarship</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/wwdc</link>
      <description>In 2019, I attended Apple's WWDC with a scholarship, a highlight of my journey learning Swift. Inspired by previous scholars, I created a playground featuring a location beacon navigating city obstacles, learning new frameworks along the way. The intense preparation period involved sleepless nights, YouTube tutorials, and constant refinements. At WWDC, I connected with inspiring developers, explored cutting-edge technologies, and experienced Apple's electric atmosphere. From meeting tech influencers to visiting top tech companies, it was an unforgettable adventure. I highly encourage computer science students to apply for this transformative opportunity.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:34:38 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Virus</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/virus</link>
      <description>In this post, a high school senior reflects on the gravity of the COVID-19 pandemic, as highlighted by Chris Cuomo on CNN. With impending travel restrictions, event cancellations, and school closures, the student experiences a profound mix of emotions, realizing the unprecedented changes in everyday life. Emphasizing the collective fight against the virus, the student acknowledges the importance of timely action to prevent a situation like Italy's, while also dealing with the uncertainty of their final school days being cut short.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:34:36 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schools Gone</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/schools-gone</link>
      <description>In a reflective blog post dated March 16, 2020, a high school student from New York shares their experiences as their school shuts down for a month due to the coronavirus pandemic. They reminisce about friends, track practice, and uncertainties ahead, describing the new reality of "school from home" with their sister and the emotional impact of such abrupt changes.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:34:34 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Candidate Does Not Exist</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/this-candidate-does-not-exist</link>
      <description>In April 2020, a high school student tested election integrity by creating a fake candidate, "Andrew Walz," who was verified by Twitter and listed on Ballotpedia. Using AI-generated images and minimal effort, the hoax highlighted vulnerabilities in candidate verification processes. The fake candidate was eventually discovered, leading to changes in verification policies by Ballotpedia and prompting discussions about online impersonation and election security. This real-world experiment underscores the importance of transparency and robust checks in maintaining public trust in democratic institutions.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:34:32 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Live streaming my high school graduation</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/live-streaming-my-high-school-graduation</link>
      <description>On August 8, 2020, I live-streamed my high school graduation, transforming it into a memorable virtual experience for over 3,000 live viewers. Due to the pandemic, our ceremony was held "drive-thru style," preventing many from attending in person. I used OBS software with an iPhone camera setup, overcame power and internet challenges, and implemented creative touches like student overlays. Despite technical hurdles, I managed to capture the 5.5-hour event live on YouTube, inspiring me to offer graduation live-streaming services to other schools next year.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:34:30 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Secret Elevator at Penn Station</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/the-secret-elevator-at-penn-station</link>
      <description>(No content available)</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:34:26 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The bike lane</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/the-bike-lane</link>
      <description>After moving to NYC, I’ve taken up biking daily, both for fun and errands. Adapting to city cycling, I noticed many cyclists, particularly delivery bikers, frequently run red lights. I cautiously do the same on occasion, but never rush. Despite careful riding, I’ve had close calls with cars, prompting concern for safety, especially after hearing of other tragic incidents like the recent death of Sarah Pitts. While biking is not without risks, we must stay vigilant and mindful on the road.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:34:22 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Music memories</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/music-memories</link>
      <description>Reflecting on how music has acted as a powerful anchor to the past, this post captures the author's experience of revisiting songs during the pandemic. With distinctive memories tied to about half of the 1,000 songs in their Spotify library, each track evokes vivid moments from different points in their life. From walking through a bookstore to driving to school, this narrative highlights music's unique ability to trigger detailed recollections and emotions, providing a nostalgic respite during challenging times.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:34:17 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Check &amp; Go</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/check-go</link>
      <description>After months of dealing with a stress-related foot injury, I ran in Central Park for the first time last night and loved the quiet and skyline. Reflecting on past running mottos like "sit and kick" and "check and go," I analyzed my form and corrected my left foot's inward movement. By the end of the run, my form felt improved—hopefully, a sign of recovery.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:34:15 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Groceries</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/groceries</link>
      <description>After moving out on my own, I've found joy in grocery shopping and the freedom to buy whatever I want. From diverse international foods to indulgent treats, the variety is endless, except at pricier places like Whole Foods. This abundance reminds me of Boris Yeltsin's 1989 visit to Texas' Randall's grocery store, which profoundly impacted his views on communism. The shelves filled with food underscored the stark contrast to Soviet scarcity and played a role in his later reforms. The power of a simple grocery store visit in Texas contributing to the downfall of communism is astonishing.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:34:08 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Following the rules</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/following-the-rules</link>
      <description>Navigating the Challenges of Central Park's Running Track

In a reflection on running around Central Park's reservoir, a blogger highlights the challenges of adhering to social distancing and the track's counter-clockwise, one-way rule. While many walkers ignore these guidelines, the post underscores the importance of such measures, especially for minimizing the spread of coronavirus. An anecdote about an elderly man attempting to enforce the rules sparks a discussion on societal attitudes towards rule enforcement. Despite the awkwardness, the author appreciates the effort to maintain order and safety during these times.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:34:05 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When it's all over</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/when-its-all-over</link>
      <description>Reflecting on life during and after the coronavirus pandemic, the author contemplates the uncertainty of returning to normalcy. Despite initial hopes that COVID-19 would diminish by summer 2020, the persistent virus has altered their perspective. They draw a parallel to finishing a grueling run, uncertain of the end but looking forward to relief and accomplishment. Adjusting to prolonged social distancing has changed how they view close interactions in pre-pandemic media, highlighting the lasting impact of the pandemic on their mindset and daily life.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:33:59 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pictures</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/pictures</link>
      <description>Reflecting on a train journey through scenic upstate New York, the author notes a moment encountering a deer near the Hudson River. Missing the chance to photograph it, they ponder society's compulsion to capture experiences rather than live them, citing Susan Sontag's insights on this behavior. They question how social norms influence the desire to document moments for validation rather than simply enjoying them.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:33:57 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Passing by</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/passing-by</link>
      <description>An athlete recounts the experience of running a 4x400 meter relay at a cold, dark track meet. Though the grueling event is not their specialty, they embrace the challenge amidst the loud cheers at the start and finish line. As they run, isolation sets in, paralleling the journey of life's hardships and triumphs. The momentary silence emphasizes the personal struggle and determination needed to achieve one's goals.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:33:55 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Random Jobs</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/random-jobs</link>
      <description>Experienced my first week as a Postmates delivery cyclist in NYC! Biking daily, it's not just about earning money—it's an adventure. From high-end restaurants to unique deliveries like spiked ice cream to NBC, the job’s diversity is fascinating. Despite a few beginner mistakes, the positive interactions and generous tips have been rewarding. Exploring delivery logistics has been insightful, and I’m eager to continue taking on random, part-time jobs to gain new perspectives and learn something fun and new.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:33:53 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perimeter</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/perimeter</link>
      <description>Last weekend, I completed a challenging 12-hour, 36-mile walk around Manhattan's perimeter, burning over 5,000 calories in the process. Despite encountering wrong turns, blisters, and an unexpected thunderstorm, the experience offered unique city views and personal insights. Inspired by The Great Saunter annual event, I embarked solo and felt a mix of physical exhaustion and accomplishment. Although not life-changing, the walk reinforced my love for physical challenges. If you're into adventurous feats, consider walking Manhattan’s perimeter – just don’t underestimate its demands!</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:33:51 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2021: Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/2021</link>
      <description>2021 was a vibrant, transformative year for me. I landed an internship at MSCHF using a creative sidewalk newspaper box, participated in multiple races in Central Park and at Icahn Stadium, and upgraded to a road bike. I moved into a co-living house in NYC, which became a pivotal part of my achievements. I explored various jobs, joined my college's D3 cross country team, and enjoyed quality moments with family. Despite minor mishaps like a stolen bike tire and a quarantined New Year's in London, I look forward to the future in NYC.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:33:48 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2022: Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/2022</link>
      <description>In 2022, I journeyed from COVID quarantine in London to a lively hostel in Amsterdam, embracing the tranquility of Edinburgh fields and the efficient German transit in Dresden. Back in New York, I relaunched Routeshuffle, biked 101 miles to Philadelphia, and filmed illegal truck idling for NYC's air quality. I dabbled in tech projects, coded a GameBoy game, and tackled endurance feats, all while fostering community spirit at Edyfi and Hack Lodge. I delved into climate change solutions, endured winter biking to Montauk, and celebrated new beginnings with family in Lisbon. A whirlwind year of travel, innovation, and personal growth.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:33:45 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unclaimed property</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/unclaimed-property</link>
      <description>Unclaimed property is a hidden issue where forgotten assets like bank accounts, gift cards, or paychecks are handed to state governments after inactivity. With over $100 billion in unclaimed funds, 1 in 7 Americans are owed money. However, governments seldom inform the public, as they earn interest on these funds. Mehran and I attempted to address this by helping people and businesses claim their money, but faced challenges due to skepticism and logistical difficulties. Despite the potential, the industry demands extensive relationships and legal navigation, leading us to abandon the venture, yet hopeful for future solutions.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:33:43 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023: Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/2023</link>
      <description>From moving to San Francisco on a whim to co-founding a startup, 2023 was a transformative year for me. I experienced the thrill of working in a fast-paced environment, spent valuable time with family, and even pulled off elaborate pranks with friends. Participating in an accelerator program honed my skills and broadened my horizons. As I look back, I recognize 2023 as a year of immense growth, learning, and adventure. Excited for 2024 and all the new questions and opportunities it promises!</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:33:40 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What a small world</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/small-world</link>
      <description>Discovering fascinating connections between friends, I scraped and analyzed my Instagram social graph, revealing a network of over 217,000 relationships. By mapping and visualizing these connections, I explored how friends from various life stages and locations are intertwined. Using SQL, I identified mutual friends across different social circles, uncovering amusing, small-world scenarios. For instance, a friend from a California cycling trip connected to my high school cross country teammate via a summer camp friend—a testament to how interconnected our lives truly are.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:33:37 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024: Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/2024</link>
      <description>2024 was a year of adventures and personal growth. From attempting a 51-mile walk around San Francisco to cycling to Los Angeles, and even organizing a massive scavenger hunt, the year was packed with physical challenges and community events. I also tackled back pain, created passion projects with friends, and enjoyed unique travel experiences in Japan. Highlights included seeing an eclipse in Illinois, participating in a freeze mob, and developing quirky tech projects like the Fast Food Index and Bop Spotter. Ending the year in Spain with family, it’s been a whirlwind of experiences and achievements.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:33:35 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
