<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Walzr</title>
    <link>https://walzr.com/</link>
    <description>All posts from walzr.com auto-generated into RSS</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 19:42:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>New project</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/new-project</link>
      <description>I’m building Routeshuffle, a simple website for generating random running, biking, and walking routes. Excited to create something better than existing options like outdated Routeloops and MapMyRun’s Route Genius, which is paywalled. Using Node.js for the first time, along with Express, Sendgrid, and Stripe, and learning a ton. Built entirely on my Chromebook! Aiming to launch early next year—stay tuned for updates!</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Touring Google</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/touring-google</link>
      <description>I recently had the incredible opportunity to tour Google’s Venice Beach offices and YouTube’s La Playa Space after winning the Mentor Foundation USA’s “Living The Example” contest. From the vibrant, collaborative workspaces to the endless perks like free meals, dog parks, and even a barbershop in a retro camper, Google’s innovative culture blew me away. At YouTube, I learned how creators use their state-of-the-art studios to produce content. It was an inspiring day filled with tech, creativity, and amazing people. Huge thanks to everyone who made this unforgettable experience possible!</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bump</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/bump</link>
      <description>As a high school runner, I’ve experienced the chaos of indoor track meets—short tracks, poor air quality, and reckless spectators crossing mid-race. My emotions shift during races, fueling a "run rage" that makes me determined to win but also angry at everything around me. This intensity isn’t limited to indoor tracks. Once, during a cross-country race, I collided with a spectator’s arm as they filmed too close to the course. Later, I learned their phone flew into the course, and I felt a strange pride. Running brings out a version of me that’s fiercely focused, no matter the cost.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WWDC scholarship</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/wwdc</link>
      <description>Winning a WWDC scholarship was a dream come true for me. As someone with no prior Swift experience, I poured my heart into creating an interactive playground featuring a car navigating a city map with random obstacles. I meticulously studied past submissions, incorporated new frameworks like Natural Language, and worked tirelessly for weeks. The effort paid off when I received the acceptance email. Attending WWDC 2019 was unforgettable—meeting inspiring people, exploring new technologies, and soaking in the vibrant atmosphere. This journey taught me the power of perseverance and passion. If you’re passionate about coding, I highly encourage you to apply—it’s an experience like no other!</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Virus</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/virus</link>
      <description>Last night, watching the news, it hit me just how much the world is changing because of the coronavirus. Travel bans, school closures, canceled events—life as we know it is shifting. I felt a mix of anger and fear, realizing this isn’t just a health crisis but a fight for normalcy. As a high school senior, I’m holding onto every moment, knowing things could change any day. It’s scary, but if we act responsibly, we can get through this. This is our new reality, and we have to face it together.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schools Gone</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/schools-gone</link>
      <description>I never imagined the coronavirus would hit New York and disrupt my life like this. School is canceled for a month, and I’m adjusting to learning from home with my sister. No track practice, no friends, no normalcy. Tonight, I ran alone, reminiscing about the past four years and realizing how much I’ll miss it all. Sitting on the high jump mat, I reflected on how nothing feels the same anymore. I’m holding onto hope, but it’s hard to believe things will go back to normal anytime soon. This feels like a strange, alternate reality I never saw coming.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Candidate Does Not Exist</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/this-candidate-does-not-exist</link>
      <description>I decided to test election integrity by creating a fake congressional candidate, "Andrew Walz," using AI-generated images and a simple website. To my surprise, both Ballotpedia and Twitter verified the non-existent candidate without proper checks. Concerned about the implications, I reached out to CNN, and the story gained widespread attention. While Twitter remained vague, Ballotpedia responded transparently, updating their policies. This experiment taught me about ethics, media, and the importance of accountability, and I’m glad it sparked meaningful change.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Live streaming my high school graduation</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/live-streaming-my-high-school-graduation</link>
      <description>When my high school graduation turned into a drive-thru event due to the pandemic, I volunteered to live stream it so friends and family could watch. It was my first time tackling such a project, and I faced challenges like setting up cameras, managing power, and dealing with spotty internet. Despite last-minute hiccups, the 5.5-hour stream was a success, with over 3,000 viewers. I even created custom overlays for each graduate. It was a rewarding experience, and I’m now considering offering live streaming services to other schools for future events.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Secret Elevator at Penn Station</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/the-secret-elevator-at-penn-station</link>
      <description>I discovered a secret elevator at Penn Station that lets you bypass the chaotic boarding lines and go straight to your train platform. After a quick Google search and some hesitation, I tried it out and was amazed at how smoothly it worked. No more waiting in long lines—just a quiet, efficient route to my train. A real game-changer for future trips!</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The bike lane</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/the-bike-lane</link>
      <description>I’ve been biking daily since moving to NYC, exploring the city and running errands. While I’ve adjusted to urban cycling, close calls with cars and reckless drivers remind me how dangerous it can be. A recent incident outside the city made me realize how much worse it could be in NYC’s chaos. After researching bike safety and reading about tragic accidents, I’m reminded that cycling here isn’t always safe—no matter how careful I am. My mom’s constant warnings echo in my mind, but I keep riding, hoping for the best.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Music memories</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/music-memories</link>
      <description>When the pandemic changed everything, I found comfort in revisiting my Spotify library. Each song holds a vivid memory—where I was, what I was doing, and how I felt. From walking through a bookstore with my mom at 12 to running on the wrong side of the road, music brings these moments back to life. It’s incredible how a single track can transport me to a specific time and place, evoking emotions like nothing else can. These songs are more than just music; they’re snapshots of my life, tied to moments I’ll never forget.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Check &amp; Go</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/check-go</link>
      <description>Last night, I ran around Central Park’s reservoir for the first time—quiet, serene, with a stunning skyline view. Reflecting on my running journey, I revisited my race mottos: “sit and kick” for pacing and “check and go” for form. After months of dealing with a lingering injury, I noticed my left foot’s inward movement, a habit from my stress reaction. Adjusting it felt strange but promising. It’s a small step, but I’m hopeful it’s progress toward healing and better runs ahead.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Groceries</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/groceries</link>
      <description>Now that I’m living on my own, grocery shopping has become a fascinating experience. I love the freedom of choosing whatever I want, from global foods to absurd quantities like 100 potatoes. It reminds me of Boris Yeltsin’s 1989 visit to a Texas grocery store, where the abundance of food shattered his faith in communism. His awe at the shelves full of endless options made me reflect on how lucky I am to have such access. It’s wild to think a simple grocery trip could influence history so profoundly.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Following the rules</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/following-the-rules</link>
      <description>I shared my thoughts on running around Central Park’s reservoir, reflecting on the challenges of navigating a one-way track during crowded mornings. I explored why most tracks are counter-clockwise, linking it to natural phenomena and athletic advantages. I also recounted an encounter with an old man enforcing the rules, sparking a mix of judgment and gratitude. While this post feels cringe now, it captures a moment of pandemic-era observations and societal norms.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When it's all over</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/when-its-all-over</link>
      <description>Reflecting on life during the pandemic, I wonder if things will ever return to "normal." Six months ago, I assumed the virus would fade by summer, but now, as fall arrives, I’m adjusting my expectations. Pre-pandemic life feels surreal, and I’ve grown used to distancing. I compare this to high school—I thought I’d change completely, but much stayed the same. Like finishing a tough run, I keep telling myself, "it’s over," but the challenge persists. I hope for that moment of relief soon, but for now, I’m learning to adapt and find pride in enduring.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pictures</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/pictures</link>
      <description>I was on an Amtrak train heading home to upstate New York, soaking in the stunning Adirondack route along the Hudson River. I spotted a deer neck-deep in the water and instinctively reached for my phone to capture it, but the train sped by too quickly. Frustrated, I realized how often I prioritize documenting moments over truly experiencing them. Susan Sontag’s insights on photography and our need to “prove” experiences resonated deeply. It’s a strange habit—trading presence for proof, as if a photo makes the moment—or me—more valid. Maybe it’s time to just live in the moment.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Passing by</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/passing-by</link>
      <description>At a cold, dark track meet, I ran the 4x400 relay—a grueling final event after a long day of races. Starting off, the cheers were deafening, but once I was running, it was just me, my footsteps, and my breath. Handing off the baton brought the noise back, but in between, I was alone. It reminded me how life works: people notice your beginnings and endings, but the hard work in between is a solitary grind. You push yourself when no one’s watching, and that’s where the real growth happens.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Random Jobs</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/random-jobs</link>
      <description>I recently became a Postmates delivery cyclist in NYC, not just for the money but to add purpose to my daily bike rides. So far, I’ve done eight deliveries, picking up food from unique restaurants and delivering to everything from luxury buildings to affordable housing. The most random? Dropping off spiked ice cream to an NBC office. I’ve made mistakes, like knocking on the wrong door, but people have been kind and still tipped. It’s been eye-opening to see the logistics behind deliveries. I want to keep taking on random, part-time jobs—the kind I thought were cool as a kid—to learn and gain new perspectives.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perimeter</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/perimeter</link>
      <description>Last weekend, I walked 36 miles around Manhattan in 12 hours—65,000 steps, 5,000 calories, and a few wrong turns later, I finished. Inspired by past challenges like biking 85 miles along the Hudson, I wanted to push myself again. The walk wasn’t life-changing, but it was insightful. From Harlem to Inwood, along the Hudson, and through a thunderstorm, I saw the city in a new way. My feet screamed by the end, but I’m glad I did it. If you’re up for a challenge, walk the perimeter—just bring extra socks and water!</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2021: Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/2021</link>
      <description>2021 was a year of bold moves, growth, and unforgettable experiences. I landed an internship at MSCHF with a creative stunt, ran races, biked, and explored NYC. Living in a co-living house brought amazing people and opportunities into my life. I worked odd jobs, built an app with friends, and even went viral on TikTok. From cross-country running to hiking on my remote property, I pushed my limits. Despite some setbacks—like a stolen bike tire and a COVID quarantine—I’m ending the year grateful for the adventures, connections, and lessons learned. Here’s to an even better 2022!</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2022: Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/2022</link>
      <description>2022 was a year of adventure, growth, and creativity for me. From being stranded in London with COVID to exploring Scotland, Amsterdam, and Dresden, I reconnected with old memories and embraced new experiences. I relaunched Routeshuffle, biked my first century, and even got involved in NYC’s idling truck reporting culture. Living at Edyfi and Hack Lodge brought incredible connections and collaborations, while projects like Hopscotch.nyc and a GameBoy game for MSCHF pushed my creativity. From cross-country running to biking to Montauk, I challenged myself physically and mentally. Grateful for the journey and excited for what’s next!</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unclaimed property</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/unclaimed-property</link>
      <description>I explored the world of unclaimed property funds, where billions sit unclaimed because people don’t know they’re owed money. I tried helping individuals and businesses recover their funds, but trust issues, scalability challenges, and the complexity of the process made it unsustainable. Despite creative outreach and cold calls, the lack of straightforward compensation for solving this information problem led me to step back. It’s a fascinating issue, but meaningful change likely requires government intervention. I hope someone cracks this someday—there’s so much money waiting to be claimed!</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023: Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/2023</link>
      <description>2023 was a year of transformation and adventure. I moved to San Francisco on a week’s notice, co-founded an AI startup, and embraced “adulting” like never before. From viral projects and wild pranks (like turning a fake Google Maps listing into a real restaurant) to sneaking into APEC and exploring national parks, every moment was a lesson in creativity and resilience. I grew personally and professionally, learned to embrace therapy, and discovered the joy of building meaningful connections. Grateful for the chaos, the growth, and the incredible people who made it all possible. Here’s to 2024 and whatever comes next!</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What a small world</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/small-world</link>
      <description>I love discovering how interconnected the world is through the "name game"—asking new people if they know someone from my life. To explore this further, I scraped my Instagram social graph, mapping 233 connections and over 217,000 relationships. Visualizing these links revealed fascinating overlaps, like friends from different parts of my life connected through mutual acquaintances. I even found 10 surprising connections, like a cycling trip friend linked to my high school cross-country teammate through summer camp and college. It’s amazing how small the world truly is!</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024: Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/2024</link>
      <description>2024 was a year of adventure, creativity, and growth. I walked 51 miles around SF (twice!), biked from SF to LA, and ran a 4x4x24 challenge. I launched projects like Bop Spotter, IMG_0001, and Ord, and co-created Pursuit, a city-wide scavenger hunt. I solo traveled to Japan, survived a freeze mob, and even got mentioned in *The Washington Post* three times. Despite battling back pain, I pushed through with stretches and support. Moved into a great apartment, kept Numerus.ai running, and ended the year with family in Spain. Here’s to 2025—more adventures await!</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
