<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Walzr</title>
    <link>https://walzr.com/</link>
    <description>All posts from walzr.com auto-generated into RSS</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 08:27:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>New project</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/new-project</link>
      <description>New projectNovember 05, 2017I am building a new website now. It's called Routeshuffle. It will be a simple site for generating random routes for running, biking and walking. I'm really excited about it. Here's some stuff about it that I've been thinking about.CompetitionThere are really only two other sites that are similar, but I think that Routeshuffle will be better than them.Routeloopshasn't been updated in years. There isn't much design and it lacks key features such as sign in and exporting to other platforms, like Google Maps for example.MapMyRun's Route Geniusis only for paying members and the features are directly pulled from Routeloops, so they are basically the same product.This probably won't be a service that people are thinking they need even before it's made, but it will help them get out the door and make it easier to generate routes for exercise. I'll have to make something that seems really awesome.BuildingI am using just Node.js to build it. It will be my first Node experience, so I'm learning a lot. I'm making it on a Chromebook, and Node has worked just as well on there than on our iMac. It was surprising. I'm also using Express, Sendgrid and Stripe.Will keep this post updated as I go on. Expect it to be out early next year.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Touring Google</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/touring-google</link>
      <description>Touring GoogleDecember 10, 2017After winning a video contest a few months ago through Mentor Foundation USA that was covered on theBallston Journal, I was finally on my way to Los Angeles as part of the first place prize.The foundation exists to help prevent drug usage within youth and to help them realize their full potential. The contest was called “Living The Example,” and its aim was to find teens that are doing just that.I was stoked to find out we would visit the Google offices in Venice Beach and the YouTube Space and offices in La Playa. I love Google; it’s a part of everyone’s lives today. I feel like I say the word “google” as a verb in every other sentence.Gudrun Giddings, the CEO at G4C Innovation where she also writes and produces films, and the president of the Swedish American Chamber of Commerce in Los Angeles, met us at our hotel to drive and go on the tour with us. She is a very nice person and happens to be a board member for Mentor Foundation USA. She was just as excited to visit the offices as we were, and as an executive and head of a Hollywood film company was interested to see how Google operated.Our first stop is Google in Venice Beach. When we walked up to the building, you could instantly feel the ‘tech’ vibe. Huge glass doors, plants everywhere, exposed brick and TVs flashing the Google logo.Photo: © Riley WalzEach of us needed to sign in on an automated kiosk with our name, person from Google we were meeting with, and the reason of our visit. The entire process was very efficient and fast, but I would expect nothing less of Google. We met up with Marc Powell, a staff member for Google. His primary job is to work with studios and producers to bring content to Google’s platforms, such as Google Play and YouTube.We then walked through the locked doors that you can only go through unless you’re with an employee. We were greeted with a hallway with walls and the ceiling printed with a collage of Google Doodles, the themed logos that are sometimes on Google’s homepage.Photo: © Riley WalzNext, we take a left into the cafeteria. Google’s dining room is very unique, in that it serves breakfast, lunch and dinner for all of their employees forfree. Everything is free, even the in-house Starbucks. Meals are designed to be insanely healthy. I didn’t see a single employee eating a lunch from home or from another restaurant, why would they want to? There are four main parts of the room: a salad bar, the buffet line with featured dishes, a frozen yogurt machine, and a counter of drinks.Google is trying to get their employees to eat healthier by hiding junk food like food with fat and high calories in non-visible drawers. Instead, the healthier options are out for display. It works, and in their research healthier foods were chosen in favor of most of the time. While I was loading up my plate I noticed something interesting, there were signs posted to almost every food item saying to only take what you can handle to waste less food. It really stuck with me and I think I took less than what I would have without the sign.Why does my thumb look so weird in this picture??Photo: © Riley WalzGoing to sit down with the group of people I was with, I saw that the seating of the room was neat. Tables were arranged all differently and you could find a place you’d like to sit. The room wasn’t bland like a regular office break room might look like. Instead it was colorful and bright, and if I worked here I’d actually enjoy it.Photo: © Riley WalzWhile talking over lunch, I found out some of the many perks of being a Google employee. You can bring your dog to work (no cats), they’ll do your laundry, free meals, free haircuts, free electronics as long as it’s for work, a doctor on site, and the most important I thought was flexible seating. You can work anywhere on the campus for creativity and inspiration. While everyone still has their own desk or dedicated work-space, you can go outside to patio tables, inside a big open room, or a picnic table out back.Photo: © Riley WalzDuring lunch, Marc said that he’s never felt healthier. He said that during his first couple of weeks at Google he gained some weight due to the endless supply of food, but over time grew accustomed to it. Now he says he’s never eaten more vegetables in his life. He added that some people that got jobs here straight from college (and therefore know nothing else) will complain when they get pasta two days in a row, but he doesn’t take any of it for granted.Before we left the cafeteria, we each grabbed some frozen yogurt while Gudrun ran to get Starbucks down the hallway. Bringing your dirty dishes is even an efficient process at Google, there is a spinning wall with empty trays in the corner of the cafeteria. Just set your plate on one of the trays and it’s whisked away to be cleaned.Next, we enter a large, airy and open room with flexible seating and large windows. The Starbucks is to the right, and you can see colorful murals through the windows outside.Photo: © Riley WalzWe continue right at the end of the room and enter an office. Everyone is deep into their work. Although there are cubicles, they aren’t the kinds that have high walls and no one is completely isolated, allowing for a more collaborative workspace. Something caught my eye: is that a liquor cabinet? When I ask Marc, he says that it is alcohol, but shrugged it off as no big deal. No one gets wasted, I guess.Continuing through the room, we get to a door to go outside. There is a large awning with bikes underneath. Most of which are ones people rode from home, but others are Google owned that anyone can use. We were near the Santa Monica bike trail, where cycling is insanely popular, but it was still quite impressive that this many people used bikes.Photo: © Riley WalzIn the picture, you can even see surfboards. Because we are only a few blocks from the ocean, Google encourages their employees to surf during a break. One has the word “GOOGLE” on it.Photo: Gudrun Ginnings/SACC-LATo the right, further from the bikes, is a fenced in mini-yard. Marc tells us that it’s a dog park for the pets in the office, much to my mom and Gudrun’s surprise.Photo: © Riley WalzTo the left, we see a retro camper, the kind that you can attach to a car. Marc tells us that it’s just another place for flexible seating. I look inside and it appears to be a barbershop. When I tell him, he’s surprised, he didn’t know all the benefits he has at Google!Photo: © Riley WalzWe go back inside through the office space and cafeteria to the street outside. We cross Hampton Drive and see a tall gate. A running joke at Google is the “tailgator.” Google employees are reminded to see if other people entering buildings with them also have badges, otherwise, they could be a “tailgator”. This is depicted in different cartoons on doors in Google with an alligator, hence the name.Photo: © Riley WalzThere is a ton of seating where people are eating their lunch and working away on their laptops. One guy has his dog sitting next to him. It almost feels like outdoor seating at a big restaurant.Photo: © Riley WalzWe keep walking to a juice bar. Outside is a wheelbarrow full of vegetables, which I thought was funny because there were actual fresh fruits and vegetables inside that anyone could take.Photo: © Riley WalzInside the juice bar, there are again people working inside, talking and collaborating. There are already made smoothies ready to take, and everyone grabs one. There’s also a plate of vitamins and minerals, I guess Google employees are encouraged to take supplements. Marc takes a few, acting like it’s completely normal.Photo: © Riley WalzWe’re done with Google in Venice Beach and next head to the car to drive to YouTube’s offices and studio in La Playa, only a twenty minute drive. After some confusion with road closures and the traffic situation, we arrive. Again, I can see many doors each with their own “tailgator” sticker.Photo: © Riley WalzInside, the offices are set up similarly. Very open and airy with a lot of work-space. We only spent a few minutes in the offices, as this was just a way to get to the YouTube Space.Photo: © Riley WalzEven a quote from a popular YouTuber is plastered on the wall.Photo: © Riley WalzWe go outside and start walking to the YouTube Space, which is a studio owned by Google where people with popular YouTube channels can come to learn, film using incredibly expensive equipment, and edit their videos on very powerful computers, all for free. There are nine locations with three being in the US, while the one is Los Angeles in the flagship one. So, why would Google do it? It certainly isn’t cheap to operate multiple studios around the world with professional equipment.Photo: © Riley WalzThe benefit to Google and YouTube is that when content producers use their studio, they have to premiere that content onto YouTube’s platforms, in turn attracting more visitors to their website and more money from advertising.Photo: © Riley WalzWhen walking in, my first impressions were the big TV with pictures from social media about the studios, the high ceilings and large windows. Again, there’s a free Starbucks and an arcade machine in the corner.Photo: © Riley WalzThe tour starts and the representative from YouTube shows us a table listing what benefits you get compared to how many subscribers you have. To shoot at all in the Space, you need at least 10,000 subscribers, and that will get you one day of shooting and three days of editing. It goes all the way up to 1,000,000 subscribers where you’ll get six days of filming and nine days of editing.Photo: Gudrun Ginnings/SACC-LAHe explained that even if you qualify to use the studios, you still need to reserve a stage or editing space online. Next to every stage, there is a monitor showing exactly what channel should be shooting now and what time they have that stage until.Photo: Gudrun Ginnings/SACC-LAIn the picture above, we saw that Professor Dave Explains was set to film in that studio, which is reserved exclusively for people with 10,000 to 100,000 subscribers. There was one other green screen studio and one white screen studio.Photo: © Riley WalzOverall, the visit to both Google and YouTube was a success. Our last stop of the day was The Fat Dog, a Swedish-owned restaurant in West Hollywood. While there I also met Emil Abedian and Caroline Stromberg, both of SACC-LA. The food was awesome and was a great way to end the day.Photo: Gudrun Ginnings/SACC-LAA special thank you to everyone who made this trip possible: Gudrun Giddings, Marc Powell, Michaela Pratt, Stacey Walz, Emil Abedian, Caroline Stromberg and the Swedish American Chamber of Commerce in Los Angeles.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bump</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/bump</link>
      <description>BumpFebruary 14, 2020As a high school runner, we go to indoor track meets during the winter when it's too cold to race outside. These indoor tracks are often really short, usually only 161 meters, and in tiny buildings. The air quality is horrible. At the end of a tough race, my throat is so dry that I feel sick. The many parents and siblings watching us narrowly fill in on the outside. But often, people (usually not athletes) cross the track in the middle of a fast race without looking, and unfortunately, get hit.I almost want to collide with these people. In a race, my emotions shift. I'm determined to finish and win and become angry. I take this anger out on anything possible. Runner's World calls this "Run Rage." I'm mad at the people running in the race with me and might elbow them. I'm angry at myself for forgetting how many laps I have left. I'm mad at the building for having such poor air quality and turns that are too sharp.This isn't just in indoor track. This year, I was running down the straightaway of a fast and tough cross country race, about to finish. I was running on the edge, next to a temporary fence. There were plenty of spectators watching along the other side of the fence. One guy, though, was filming the race and holding his phone too far over the fence. I was tired and could barely think, but I knew I was on a trajectory to run right into this guy's arm. Neither of us moved.It wasn't until a few minutes after the finish until a parent told me that what happened in the straightaway was awesome. Confused, I asked them what they meant. They said to me that the guy's phone flew into the course. I felt kind of proud of myself, but I wasn't sure why. Sure, his arm shouldn't have been over the fence, but I didn't have anything against him.Every person has many versions of themselves that come out when we face different situations. I guess one of my versions is one that doesn't care about anything when I run.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WWDC scholarship</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/wwdc</link>
      <description>WWDC scholarshipFebruary 15, 2020Apple has always been one of my favorite companies, and being able to attend WWDC in 2019 was a dream come true. I had a fantastic time, and it's a week I'll never forget.Mysubmissionwas a map showing a location beacon moving across a city map. Random obstacles showed up at random locations, and the beacon would optimize its path to get around as many obstacles as possible.As WWDC in 2018 was going on, I was following the news and saw some of the scholars' experiences on Twitter. I read Samay Shamdasani'sblog postabout winning a scholarship, and that was when it clicked: I decided I was going to give the scholarship process a shot next year.It seemed like a long shot. I had never opened a Swift file in my life. I did have experience working with JavaScript and Node.js, but never anything on Apple's ecosystem. In July, I started brainstorming ideas for my playground submission. I watched every accepted and rejected scholarship submission video I could find on YouTube, to get a sense of what worked and what didn't. Of course, I wanted to win, and because the odds were stacked against me, I had to know exactly what worked in the past. Here are the key components I repeatedly saw in winning submissions:some demo that users can watch or interact with, instead of something that instantly happens when they click a button,incorporate some real-world problem into your playground,incorporate a new Swift framework into your playground to demonstrate new technologies,document everything in the playground on the left-hand side,should be simple enough that someone who doesn't know Swift can understand,and introduce the playground with simple examples of the libraries you'll be usingThere were plenty of very technologically advanced submissions that got rejected because they didn't have personality. As I was developing my playground, I continuously went back to these points to ensure my playground had all of these qualities.I watchedthis videoon YouTube, called "Swift Programming for JavaScript Developers," which helped get familiar with how Swift is written. For example, I didn't understand why I needed to specify what type of variable I was defining, but this video cleared it up.One of the projects in JavaScript I was working on then wasRouteshuffle, a random route generator for runners. At first, my idea was to make a version of Routeshuffle for my playground, but this proved problematic because a) playgrounds are judged offline, and b) it doesn't fulfill most of the qualities I noticed winning submissions had. Over time, I morphed this idea into a simpler and more interactive one, but I didn't start working on it until March 5.At this point, my idea was having a car drive around a city map where random obstacles popped up, and the vehicle had to reroute around them. This was a solid idea, I thought, because it would satisfy point 1.I started getting the basics of working with Playgrounds in Xcode. This was a lot of watching YouTube videos, trial, and error, and asking questions in theWWDC ScholarsDiscord.I started using UIKit but quickly switched to SpriteKit.By the time the scholarship was officially announced on March 14, I didn't have much done. I just had my playground started with the basics. For the next ten days (until my submission was due on March 24), I worked non-stop. Every minute of my free-time went towards working on this, and I stayed up until midnight most nights working. Was it fun? No, but looking back, this was probably the most motivated I've ever been to get something done on time.I used sticky notes to make to-do lists and keep track of what needed to be done. Each sticky note was put into one of three categories: need to do, if you have extra time, and done. Every night before I went to bed, I wrote down what I was doing, so I could immediately jump into work the next day.The Discord chat helped me understand key concepts when I was confused.A lot of the project revolved around not very well-documented functions in Swift, so searching GitHub for code using that function was very helpful. Most of the time, looking at examples helped me understand a concept far better and faster than reading documentation on Apple's website did.Six days later, I had a decent version of the traffic simulator working. Users could enter what coordinates they wanted to get directions from, say [0,0] to [4,5]. This was a good start, but I wanted the capability for users to enter "cafe to school," and I would have a list of what coordinates these locations were. I watched several of the session videos from WWDC18 and sawone about the Natural Language framework. Word tagging can identify keywords from a string based on a machine learning model, which was exactly what I needed to do. On top of that, the framework was less than a year old, satisfying point 3.I manually wrote down plenty of examples for the ML model, and much to my surprise, it worked pretty well. Users could type in "school to cafe," "cafe from school," "How do I get from the cafe to the school?" or any other variant, and it would extract "school" as the origin, and "cafe" as the destination.To satisfy point 6, I decided to add two additional slides to my playground that would introduce the two major frameworks I was using: pathfinding with GameplayKit and word tagging with Natural Language.During school, when I was away from my computer and couldn't work on my playground, I worked on the essays necessary with submission. One is required, and the other two were optional.Tell us about the features and technologies that you used in your Swift playground, in 500 words or less.If you've shared or considered sharing your coding knowledge and enthusiasm for computer science with others, let us know in 500 words or less. (optional)If you have one or more apps on the App Store created entirely by you as an individual, tell us about them in 500 words or less. (optional)The first essay was easy to write because I was describing the flow of the playground and what was happening behind the scenes. I already knew how my playground worked inside and out. The second was a bit harder, as I had to think back to my achievements in computer science and how I've helped others. I skipped the third because I had never created an app. I had my English teacher and my computer science teacher check both of the essays before submitting them. In total, I probably spent 5 hours writing and revising.I submitted my playground 5 minutes before it was due on March 24. The next three weeks were pure waiting. Finally, April 15 was when acceptance emails were expected. I was expecting the email to be sent sometime in the afternoon. My Apple ID email is an ancient AOL one, so I had to manually log in to AOL's website every time I wanted to check to see if the email arrived.Finally, at 7 pm local time, I saw atweetfrom an Apple Developer PR person congratulating all of the winners. This was it. My heart rate was off the charts as I checked my email. The screen flashed, and I saw the words "You've been awarded..." and I was so happy. All of the hard work and time spent paid off.Can't believe it, but I won a WWDC scholarship!pic.twitter.com/1qsX58GrrK— Riley Walz (@rtwlz)April 15, 2019*(Ironic, because this tweet was sent from "Twitter for Android")*Early Saturday morning on June 3, I boarded an Amtrak train from Albany to Penn Station, trekked across New York City to an obscure bus station (to avoid the Airtrain at all costs), and got to JFK. My flight landed in SFO, where I took the Caltrain to San Jose Diridon and rode my first Bird to the dorms at San Jose State University, where Apple was providing lodging.These things are fast!On Sunday, we took the short walk to the convention center to get our badges and jackets. The plaza in front of the convention center is open and sunny, and music (primarily songs from Apple commercials) was playing on big speakers from across the street. It's hard to explain, but the vibe was incredible.Later in the afternoon, the scholarship kickoff was held at Discovery Meadow, a park down the street from the convention center. More than 50 Apple engineers were there to chat about their careers and just about anything. It was interesting listening to their stories and why they enjoyed their work.iJustineeven appeared, and I got a picture with her.Apple flies out some of the best employees from its retail stores across the country to work logistics for the event. Because the scholars have a different colored badge than regular attendees, they will cheer something like "We've got a scholar in the house!" and clap and cheer whenever you walk by them.On Monday, the big keynote was a blast. Many times during the presentation I couldn't believe I was actually here, intheroom.Monday night I went to a live recording of the Accidental Tech Podcast.On Tuesday, I headed into San Francisco to visit a web engineer at Twitter's headquarters. Because of delays on the BART (which I should have accounted for), I was a few minutes late to the meeting and was sprinting down Market Street. The security at Twitter is top-notch. They have someone in the lobby of the building to verify your name is on the list, then they send you up in the elevator. Then, I needed to show my driver's license to the staff upstairs and wear a visitor's badge.The visit to Twitter was amazing. The open-air space they have set up seemed like a really nice place to get work done.Back in San Jose, I went to many of the sessions throughout the week and learned a lot about new features in Swift and on the software side of iOS. I met so many inspirational students that were doing and making incredible things. There were so many smart people to learn from in one place.On Thursday, I took the tram to Mountain View and visitedNathan Leungat Google where he was interning. It was cool to walk around the huge campus and get lunch at the cafeteria. I will definitely apply for internships at SV companies in college.That night, Weezer took the stage at Discovery Meadow for the bash. Afterwards, a group of us went birding around San Jose.Finally, Friday. The last day of the conference. It was sad to say good-bye. I tried making the most out of the day.The Scholarship Lounge, seconds before it closed for good on Friday. This was where the scholars could hang out between sessions and connect with each other. There were a lot of good discussions in here.A view from the deck at the convention center an hour before it closed on Friday.On Saturday morning, I left San Jose and went into San Francisco to meet with a few people I had met on Twitter. Being able to meet people IRL who I met online was a cool way to end the trip.During the afternoon, I walked around SF while hauling my luggage around. I walked from Pacific Heights to the Twin Peaks. It was a really scenic (but hilly) walk. Then I went back to North Point to get a bowl of clam chowder before my flight left. I underestimated how much time I had and because there were no trams for some reason along the Embarcadero, I had to hurry to the Embarcadero BART station to get to the airport on time.Overall, it was an amazing trip! I think all students with an interest in computer science and attending the conference should apply for a scholarship.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Virus</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/virus</link>
      <description>VirusMarch 12, 2020I was flipping through news channels last night when Chris Cuomo was wrapping his show up on CNN.Listen, this is a time to be honest with one another. We are in a new normal, and we don't know how long it's going to last.But as the President told you tonight, it's going to change, and there is going to be limited travel from Europe for the next 30 days. There will be some exceptions. Obviously, if you are a United States resident, it's different.But the NBA cancelled games. You're going to see more of it. Schools are going to close. You're going to see more of it. Your ability to do what you want to do, when you want to do it, how you want to do it, no matter where you live, it's going to change. But remember why.If we do the right things now - I know we got a late start. I know there is blame for that. You got to put it to the side because you've got to get better now. If you do it now, you won't be Italy. You will get better faster. That's the hope.Now, I have been following news about the coronavirus over the last few months. But at that moment, it really struck me just how big of a deal this is. I know I have nothing to be worried about ifIget sick, but my way of life will change in a way that it never has before. I was overcome with anger, fear and emotion. I imagine it's what people feel as they enlisted to fight in wars, except there is no war in that sense now. It's humanity versus a virus.As a senior in high school, I'm taking every single school day like it could be my last. School and sports will likely be cancelled soon, but there's no telling when.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schools Gone</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/schools-gone</link>
      <description>Schools GoneMarch 16, 2020Never did I think the coronavirus would ever get to New York and have a direct effect on me. Yet, here we are, roughly 3 months since the virus emerged. Out of an abundance of caution, my school has been cancelled for the next month. That means no more seeing my friends every day and no more track practice. I'm holding out hope that after this month of social distancing is over, everything will return back to normal and I can finish out the last month of high school strong. It doesn't seem likely, though.Tomorrow is the first day of "school from home." My sister and I set up a table to do our work from for the next five weeks. We are trying to keep each other accountable by doing our work near each other, even though we don't take the same classes. This just feels like some crazed alternative universe scenario.I went on a run by myself tonight. I went to the street where the team runs for warm-ups at the start of each practice. I don't think you realize how important something is until it's gone. Memories from the past four years flooded my head as I looked around. So many positive things. I ran up the hill and went to the track. I sat on a high jump mat for awhile and reflected on everything that's happened. It seems like nothing will be normal for a long time.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Candidate Does Not Exist</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/this-candidate-does-not-exist</link>
      <description>This Candidate Does Not ExistApril 21, 2020A story about impersonation, election integrity and being in the mediaIn my high school history class, we learned about election integrity and how phishing campaigns and social media bots affected the US election in 2016. This got me thinking, could something like this happen again in 2020?In December, Twitterchanged its policyon verifying candidates. Previously, congressional and gubernatorial candidates needed to win their party's primary before their Twitter accounts could get verified. Now, any candidate running in a primary could have their account verified. Just like during the midterm elections in 2018, Twitter would also bepartnering with Ballotpedia, a non-profit political encyclopedia, to identify candidates to verify.I wanted to test if Ballotpedia and Twitter would verify a completely non-existent candidate. I remember telling my sister about my idea, and we both laughed. I had the idea in the back of my mind for a while and finally asked myself, "Why don't I just do it?" It was the middle of Christmas break, my girlfriend was out of town and I was kind of bored. I made a website and Twitter account for a fake candidate, named "Andrew Walz," running in Rhode Island's 1st Congressional District. The site took me around 20 minutes to make with a website builder and boilerplate copy.The candidate's profile picture was generated withThis Person Does Not Exist, a website that produces images of non-existent people using artificial intelligence.I submitted the fake candidate's information to Ballotpedia, and within a week (around January 1st), the information was on their website, and Andrew Walz had his own entry.On February 7, Twitter sent an email saying they were going to verify the account, but needed it to have a header photo first.This was simple enough to do, so I added a header photo and sent a reply saying what I had done.On February 9, the account was verified.First off, I was surprised that Twitter was proactive in reaching out to Andrew Walz. I didn't do anything to get their attention. Second, I was concerned because Twitter never asked for documents to prove Andrew Walz's identity, such as a government-issued ID. Because this candidate is fake, I never filed anything with the Federal Election Commission to register to get on the ballot. Twitter or Ballotpedia could have checked public FEC records to see whether this candidate was official (it is illegal to file false information with the FEC). This fake candidate also never received any press or mentions in media outlets, which should be an additional red flag.If I could do this with little time and money, imagine what a highly-skilled team of people looking to do actual damage could do. Knowing full-well that I shouldn't have been able to do this, I decided to reach out to reporters. Why didn't I go directly to Twitter or Ballotpedia? They likely wouldn't have done enough to fix this in the long-term. I think that they would have suspended the account and moved along. With the story being out there in the open, I hoped that both organizations would be forced to do something to prevent this from happening again.I reached out to CNN'sDonie O'Sullivan, who interviewed me about the incident at my high school in mid-February. It went smoothly, and I'm thankful for the crew's attention to detail.CNN publishedthe storyon February 28. My name was withheld because my family wasn't sure what the response to the story would be. I didn't want my college applications to be negatively affected. Almost all of the reactions about the story were positive, though.Twitter suspended the account but didn't say much in their statements to news outlets about what happened.On the other hand, Ballotpedia had a very transparent response and outlined everything that happened on their end and what policies they were changing in a page titledLegitimacy of Andrew Walz 2020 election candidacy and Ballotpedia profile. They updated theirdefinition of a candidateto have a FEC ID number before they are included in Ballotpedia's database of candidates. Ballotpedia's CEO later published a statement and overview of the events that happened in an article calledThe Andrew Walz hoax candidacy. I admire their response and how they handled this situation. If more companies and organizations responded to controversy transparently like this, the world would be a better place.Seeing the response from other media outlets and social media was a fascinating experience. Other outlets, like the New York Post, Insider, and Engadget covered the story.Barstool Sportscalled me a "random ass teenager," aCanadian news showfor kids talked about it, apodcastcalled me a "well-to-do internet troll," and aresearch paperfrom Google Brain and the UC Berkeley called it a "fairly innocuous prank."This was a big lesson in ethics and the media for me. While I was debating whether to come forward, I didn't want to regret my decision later. Ultimately, I'm happy with what happened and am glad that some change came from it.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Live streaming my high school graduation</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/live-streaming-my-high-school-graduation</link>
      <description>Live streaming my high school graduationAugust 08, 2020A few days ago, I finally graduated high school.But that's not the point of this post. Graduation is usually at a big concert venue, but due to the pandemic, it had to be done "drive-thru style" in the bus loop of my high school. This meant that extended family and friends wouldn't be able to attend. I offered to volunteer and live stream the graduation, and the school administration happily agreed.I had never live streamed an event like this, so learning where to start and how to overcome logistical challenges was an interesting quarantine task.Streaming softwareThe first thing I had to figure out was what software to use to actually stream. Whatever software I used had to do these things:switch between at least two camerasstream for hours at a time (the event would be 5.5 hours)show overlaysI foundSwitcher Studio, an app for iOS, which supported multiple cameras but they had to be either iPhones or iPads. I ended up going withOBS, the standard open-source software for streaming on desktop. I found an app calledOBS Camerathat let me plug my iPhone in via USB and get a low latency camera input in OBS.Getting powerChoosing where to put the computer that would run OBS was difficult. I needed power. I could put it on the side of the stage, but getting a wired connection to the camera facing the stage would be impossible because the cable couldn't go in the road. Putting the computer on the sidewalk across from the stage was preferable, but there were no power outlets on that side of the road.The school ended up parking an empty van on the side of the road across from the stage, leaving the engine running all-day and hooking an extension cable into the car battery. Not the best solution, but it worked and was reliable.Internet connectionThe school building was too far away to get a wired Ethernet connection, so it had to be wireless. The school gave me a Verizon hotspot to try, but Verizon service was unreliable in that location. The T-Mobile service on my phone gave around 4 Mb/s in upload speed, which was good. I tested both a few days before in the spot I would setup at.Finishing touchesI bought a few extra long USB extensions cables. I got my sister and some of our friends to help out, so one of them would hold an iPhone on a monopod. The iPhone would be plugged into a PC on the long USB extension cable. They would run into the road once the car parked. The graduate would get out of the car, cross the stage, and the camera would follow them across. Once they exited, the cameraperson would get out of the way of the car, and repeat.Another camera would be zip-tied to a flagpole to get a wide overhead shot of the entire stage.I also wrote a script to scrape the school website, download each student's senior picture, and generate a transparent overlay of each student and their name. This overlay would be shown on the stream as they crossed the stage. Because everyone had to wear a mask and their cap, I thought showing a picture with no mask would be a nice touch.The day ofI started setting everything up 1.5 hours before the graduation started. The network speed on my T-Mobile hotspot was &lt;0.1 Mb/s, an external mic I was hoping to use wasn't recognized by my PC, and only one camera was working at a time in OBS. Time flew as I was trying to fix all of this, and graduation was about to start.I got the mobile hotspot to work just in time. Putting it on the second-to-last rung on a ladder was the solution (but not the top rung). I started the stream with just one super-zoomed-out camera. During the course of the day, the service would randomly drop, but moving my phone to a new spot or height usually fixed the problem.I thought each student would be called up in alphabetical order, but because the cars arrived in jumbled order, this was not the case. At first I was squinting across the road to see who was about to be called next, and searching through a folder to find their overlay. Eventually, one of my friends helping stood next to the announcer and told me through phone call who was about be called next. This helped a lot.During a break, I got the second camera working and fixed the angle and zoom of the original one. During the course of the 5.5 hour event, the production value really shot up as stuff started to click into place.*The recorded version of the stream uploaded to YouTube after the event. Some parts were dropped during the stream, but the recording has everything.*I was one of the last students to graduate, and my dad took over the OBS streaming when I left. To say the least, he had some trouble but made it work.Things I would do differentlyUse a wired internet connectionGet everything set up 3+ hours before to make sure there are no problemsOver 3,000 people watched live, and the average watch time was around 8 minutes. The recorded version is live on YouTube for many more to watch after the fact.Since the coronavirus isn't really going anywhere, it's a possibility that graduations next year will still have limited attendance. If so, I'm aiming to reach out to surrounding school districts and offer to do paid work live streaming their graduations, using the work I did at my school as an example.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Secret Elevator at Penn Station</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/the-secret-elevator-at-penn-station</link>
      <description>The Secret Elevator at Penn StationSeptember 12, 2020I took an Amtrak train home yesterday. It was a great trip. The Adirondack route follows the Hudson River and I luckily got a seat on the scenic side of the train.The night before I left, I Googled how early I should get to Penn Station.A whole hour?No way, that's way too long. I already had my ticket on my phone and didn't need to check any bags.Common sense would make you think you could walk right up to the platform your train is going to be at. But at stations in NY, DC, Boston and Philadelphia, you have to wait until your train is called, get in line, present your ticket and then be shown to your platform. Amtrak says it's a security measure, but they don't have security screening machines and this rule is only at certain stations.This articleabout Amtrak's insane boarding procedures at big stations like Penn Station, is 6 years old but still accurate. It asks the question: "Is Amtrak unaware of the differences between planes and trains?"Some other blogs talk about a mysterious elevator in Penn Station that lets your bypass all of the line nonsense and go directly to the platform. Thelatest referenceto it was from a few years ago, so I wasn't sure if I could still take advantage of it.I got to the station 20 minutes before my train was supposed to leave. I looked at the monitor and quickly figured out what platform my train was at. I almost instantly recognized the elevator, right next to a mini Dunkin. There was a massive line for boarding right in front of the elevator. I wasn't sure what to expect when I pressed the elevator button.Almost a minute later, the elevator finally opened. I went down a floor, and came to an empty hallway with even more elevators. The hallway was obviously set up for passengers because it had signs, but it was almost uncomfortably quiet compared to the chaos upstairs. I saw a sign for my platform, got in another elevator, went down another floor and ended up on the platform. There was a line of people walking to the train, so I joined them, got on and was in shock that the elevator trick actually worked.Real life pro tip! In the future, I'll try to time it to get there 10 minutes early.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The bike lane</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/the-bike-lane</link>
      <description>The bike laneSeptember 12, 2020I moved to NYC a few weeks ago and have been biking almost everyday, usually at least 10 miles. I've mostly just been riding for fun, but also bike to get groceries, library books and do other errands.I've adjusted well to riding in a city. At first, I was shocked by how other cyclists handle the road (mostly food delivery bikers). Mostly everyone goes through red lights, some more cautious than others. Of course I go through the occasional red light, but only after looking both ways many times. I'm never in a hurry to get anywhere, so I'm not rushing like other people.I've had a couple close calls, mostly with cars turning left and not seeing me about to cross the intersection. I totally understand why this happens; 99% of the time there are no bikes, so the drivers get accustomed to not looking. While on an 80 mile ride to Newburgh, I got tapped by a driver that passed me on the left, turned into an angled parking spot and cut me off. I wasn't even in the city, instead a quiet village 30 miles north. I was completely fine and so was my bike, but it made me think that a lot worse could happen in the city, a much more chaotic and louder place.I wrote about bike lanes for a public speaking project, and read many Gothamist and Streetsblog articles about bike safety. Just a few days ago, Sarah Pitts was cycling in Brooklyn and wasstruck and killed by a busat a notorious intersection. A reporter covering many of the tragic cycling incidents tweeted the next day:What’s heartbreaking about my moms question is that I really don’t do anything differently, none of us dopic.twitter.com/7kuvpPG4HD— Julianne Cuba (@Julcuba)September 10, 2020Cycling in New York is not always safe, like a lot of things in life. I really resonated with this tweet because my mom is just like this, always telling me to be careful and I always say I am. But who knows?</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Music memories</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/music-memories</link>
      <description>Music memoriesSeptember 13, 2020When the pandemic hit and everyone's way of life dramatically changed, I fell back to listening to music from normal times. There are around 1,000 songs in my Spotify library, and I'd estimate that for about half of them, I can distinctively picture one moment where I was listening to that song long ago. I know what I was doing, where I was and what time of year it was. I suddenly remember how I felt during that time. It's crazy how music can evoke these feelings. It's really the only medium that brings back memories and emotions for me in a complete way, maybe except for pictures.The location where I remember is super specific. I'm shuffling through my library now to get some examples:R.L. Burnside - Someday Baby: I'm walking through a Barnes and Noble bookstore with my mom. It's the fall and I'm probably 12 years old. No idea why I remember this.6LACK - Switch: I'm watching dash-cam car accident videos on YouTube in my high school cafeteria after school. Also the fall. So random.Phoenix - 1901: I'm driving to school in the winter. My windshield isn't defrosted all of the way.Run-Around - Blues Traveler: It's July, probably around 8pm. I just started a run and I know exactly what intersection I was at. Now that I think about it, I was running on the wrong side of the road (with traffic).Now, Now - MJ: I'm walking my dog in August, and waiting for him to pee. I know which intersection I'm at.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Check &amp; Go</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/check-go</link>
      <description>Check &amp; GoSeptember 14, 2020I ran for the first time in Central Park last night around the reservoir. There's barely anyone there. It's quiet. You get a great view of the skyline. I probably won't run during the day in New York City anymore unless I have to.I've been dealing with a lingering injury for the past 6 months. The day coronavirus ruined our lives, March 13th, I received a second blow to the face when I got a stress reaction in my foot. That has since cleared up, but while I had that injury, I unconsciously started walking differently in my left foot. My ankle started to hurt when I ran again, but it would usually subside if I took a day or two off and only ran a few miles at a time.In the park last night, I was thinking about my "mottos" I used to use during races. At the beginning of the race, I'd usually say "sit and kick" to myself over and over again with my few remaining brain cells left to use. (In high school cross country, nobody really knows how to pace properly and the first mile is usuallywayfaster than the remaining. Sit and kick is a term for running slower in the beginning of a race and ramping your speed up as you go.)By the middle of the race, when my form (and my morale) start to deteriorate, I'd start thinking "check and go." This was code for checking my form. Making sure my arms were moving straight, I was looking straight ahead, and driving my knees.When I thought of this, I really analyzed my form. I knew my right foot had good form; it was never injured, so I compared it to my left I realized I was moving my left foot noticeably more inward when I took a step. This makes sense. During my stress reaction, doing this offloaded some of the pain off.I moved my left foot out to match my right, and it felt really weird. By the end of the run, it already felt better. Maybe it's a mental thing and I just think it feels better because I want it too... but I think it's a step in the right direction.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Groceries</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/groceries</link>
      <description>GroceriesSeptember 15, 2020Now that I'm living on my own, I'm doing a lot more grocery shopping. Every time I walk into a store, I think to myself, "wow, I can literally buy whatever I want." I can get many varieties of food originating from all over the world for not much money (except if you're at a Whole Foods, I've discovered). If I want to buy 100 potatoes and be like one of those people described in middle school math problems, I can.Boris Yeltsin, newly elected leader of the Soviet Union, visited the Johnson Space Center in 1989. Afterwards, he madean unplanned stop at a Randall's grocery storein Clear Lake, Texas. He was in awe of the amount and variety of food anyone could buy. He didn't even get this much food as the Soviet head.In Yeltsin’s own autobiography, he wrote about the experience at Randall’s, which shattered his view of communism, according to pundits. Two years later, he left the Communist Party and began making reforms to turn the economic tide in Russia. You can blame those frozen Jell-O Pudding pops.“When I saw those shelves crammed with hundreds, thousands of cans, cartons and goods of every possible sort, for the first time I felt quite frankly sick with despair for the Soviet people,” Yeltsin wrote. “That such a potentially super-rich country as ours has been brought to a state of such poverty! It is terrible to think of it.”It's crazy to think that a quick visit to a grocery store in Texas contributed to the defeat of communism.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Following the rules</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/following-the-rules</link>
      <description>Following the rulesSeptember 16, 20202023 update, this post is cringe to me now but I'll leave it upI've been running more and more around the reservoir around Central Park. Today, I ran in the morning, when it's relatively crowded. The trail is about 6 feet wide, and on top of trying to social distance, it can be a challenge trying to pass people. While it's designated as a running track, a majority of people are walking (which is allowed).The track is one-way. There are signs that say this at every entrance. You're supposed to go counter-clockwise.Side note: why is virtually every track in the world counter-clockwise? I guess there'sa reason why.We run counter-clockwise because everything in nature tends towards counter-clockwise motion. The list of natural phenomena that run counterclockwise is quite impressive. It includes: the molecule structure of amino acids, the shape of seashells, the rotational direction of all the planets (except Venus), and the orbital direction of the earth around the sun. On this point, Peter Brown from Sheffield argues: “Because of the effect of the Earth`s rotation, an athlete running anti-clockwise will have a slight advantage, resulting in a faster time. In the Southern Hemisphere, this effect is reversed but, as the sport grew up in the Northern Hemisphere, anti-clockwise races have remained, despite the international status of athletics. Evidence of this phenomenon is that none of the current world track records have been set south of the equator.But anyway, the occasional person will be running or walking in the wrong direction. I mean, if they went the other way, they'd be going faster!It's not too annoying to pass a person going the wrong way, but the rule is in place for a reason. Especially in the wake of coronavirus, one-way paths can stop the spread of coronavirus by limiting the number of times people pass one another.I saw an old guy walking on the left of the path, on a trajectory to crash into a group of people walking the wrong way. He wasn't budging, and ran into them, before yelling that the track was one-way. And that dogs weren't allowed. They continued going the wrong way.What does society think of this guy? I think the average person would look down on him for trying to enforce a seemingly trivial rule. But I couldn't help but yell out a "thank you."</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When it's all over</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/when-its-all-over</link>
      <description>When it's all overSeptember 17, 2020What will life look like after the coronavirus? Will things ever return to normal? 6 months from now, will things actually change? In the spring, I made a lot of decisions assuming that the virus would be gone by the end of the summer. Now that we're into the fall and there's no sign it's slowing down, I need to adjust my thinking.At the same time, I feel so used to the virus and social distancing, that sometimes when I see a picture or video pre-pandemic of people close together, I do a double take. "That's not allowed!"I think it's natural to assume that in 6 months, a year or even 5 years, your life will look so much different. At the beginning of high school, I remember thinking about what kind of person I'd be at the end of those 4 years. I thought I'd be a completely different person. To that end, I definitely learned a lot about myself and the world in high school, but my life is a lot of the same: mostly the same interests, motivations, friends, opinions.I relate a lot of things back to running. During a workout, when I would finish the last rep and I was dying to catch my breath, I'd think over and over to myself "it's over, it's over, it's over." In that moment, it was hard to imagine not being breathless. The reps just kept coming. I couldn't believe that was the last one. It made me happy and proud that I finished the challenging run. I'm hoping that moment for the virus will come soon, but it's not likely.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pictures</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/pictures</link>
      <description>PicturesSeptember 18, 2020I'm on an Amtrak train going home to upstate New York. The Adirondack route is very scenic. Most of the time you're right alongside the Hudson River. I saw a deer neck-deep in the water. My first thought was to take a picture of it. The train flew by, so I didn't have enough time. I get mildly disgusted with myself when this happens. I'd rather just enjoy the moment.A lot of this probably has to do with social norms. If I tell someone later that I saw a deer in the water, they'd probably think it was interesting. But if I show them a picture, they'd think it was much cooler, and as a result, might think I'm cool. As a write this, I realize how stupid and true this is.Susan Sontagwrote about this phenomenonover 40 years ago, way before every person became armed with a smartphone.Most tourists feel compelled to put the camera between themselves and whatever is remarkable that they encounter. Unsure of other responses, they take a picture. This gives shape to experience: stop, take a photograph, and move on. The method especially appeals to people handicapped by a ruthless work ethic: Germans, Japanese, and Americans. Using a camera appeases the anxiety which the work-driven feel about not working when they ­are on vacation and supposed to be having fun. They have something to do that is like a friendly imitation of work: they can take pictures.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Passing by</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/passing-by</link>
      <description>Passing bySeptember 20, 2020I'm at a track meet. It's dark and cold. We're onto the last event, the exciting, chaotic, and usually dreaded 4 by 400 meter relay. Coaches all over the country find joy in putting their distance runners in the 4x4. Everyone's already run the mile, 2 mile, steeplechase, 800 meters, or usually some combination. It's one last punch in the face before we go home. We're not trying to win because we don't train specifically for this event, but it's good practice and pushes us to our limits after a long day.Coaches, parents, and other athletes are always huddled by the start/finish line, cheering on the baton handoffs. I'm starting the team off, so I step to the line in my lane. The gun goes off and so do my legs. Everyone's screaming and cheering for their team. It's loud.15 seconds later,dead silence. I feel isolated. It's just me and the other people running. All I hear are my footsteps and heavy breathing. About a minute since it started, I'm back where I began handing the baton off. More loud cheering.Life is a lot life this race. People only really care about your achievements and challenges when you start and finish them. When you're working hard on the other side of the track, you're alone and have to push yourself.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Random Jobs</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/random-jobs</link>
      <description>Random JobsSeptember 24, 2020I signed up to a Postmates delivery cyclist in NYC last week. Normally I go and bike around for an hour or so everyday. I'm not doing it just for the money. I thought it'd be nice to have a purpose while I'm already cycling around.The jobs have been really interesting. I've only done eight deliveries, but have picked up food from very distinct restaurants, and delivered to luxury buildings, regular building, affordable housing. The most random one was dropping off spiked ice cream to an NBC office. I've made mistakes, like knocking on the wrong door or ringing the wrong apartment. But people have been really nice and usually tip even if I mess something up or show up late.Everyone has gotten something delivered, but getting to know the logistics behind how deliveries work has been insightful.Throughout life, I want to take on random, part-time jobs. The kinds of jobs I thought were cool as a kid (and still do). Just to learn something and get a different perspective.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perimeter</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/perimeter</link>
      <description>PerimeterNovember 16, 2021Last weekend, I walked 36 miles around the entire perimeter of Manhattan, all in one day. It took nearly 12 hours, 65,000 steps, and over 5,000 calories.In September 2020, I biked 85 miles along the Hudson River to New Hamburg, a small hamlet upstate. This was a spontaneous decision and a tough challenge. My phone died at mile 75, and there were multiple times where I took a wrong turn only to realize my mistake a mile or two later. I didn't stop enough to get water either and felt not great the week after. It was a very beautiful ride, especially with the fall foliage!I wanted to do another physical challenge this fall. I was playing around with measurements in Google Maps. My initial ideas were biking the perimeter of New York City or biking from Queens to Montauk. Walking the 32-mile perimeter of Manhattan caught my attention when I realized it was already a semi-formal event each year calledThe Great Saunter. Upwards of a thousand people usually walk the perimeter together in May, but I didn't want to wait until then. I planned to "saunter" the second weekend in November, as my cross country running season ended and gave me some time to recover from running.One blog post fromJeff Fleishmanmade me even more up for the challenge:Was it a good experience? Sure. Was it cool to see the city from so many different angles? Yeah, I guess. But, I’m not going to sit here and claim that despite the pain, the whole thing was worth it. It wasn’t! It really wasn’t!Don’t ever do this. Your body will hate you. Your feet will want to secede from your legs. Your spirit will be drained. You will probably get lost. STAY AWAY AND DON’T EVER THINK ABOUT DOING THIS. Manahattan is a big, biiiiig island, and we’re not supposed to walk around it.Saturday morningI took the subway to Lexington Avenue and 125th Street and started there at 10:15 a.m. I decided to walk counter-clockwise. The first 10 or so miles were a breeze alongside the Harlem River and under The High Bridge.I reached Inwood. I hadn't been there before. I only knew it from seeing it at the top of maps as the northern-most neighborhood of Manhattan. It's like the Montauk or Svalbard of the borough. Along the route, there was a convenient farmer's market, where I stopped to get an apple. I then entered Inwood Hill Park. It didn't feel like I was in the city anymore. I was brought onto a hiking path along a cliff, with a view out into The Bronx. I could see a train approaching the Spuyten Duyvil Metro-North station from the other side of the creek.I was now heading south along the western coast. I should have turned at Dyckman Street away from the water to avoid a dead-end. I only realized my mistake when I hit the end of that path an odd 1.5 miles later. The path I needed to be on was only a few hundred meters away, but a highway, cliff, and active railroad was separating me from the right path. I was forced to back-track and walk 3 miles more than I needed to.Once I was on the right path, I was perched high up alongside the Henry Hudson Parkway. I took a beat at Inspiration Point, a neoclassical resting point with a view of the George Washington Bridge. (The highway is 20 yards behind the camera, so it's not as peaceful as it looks.)This was around where I reached 15 miles. My feet felt relatively good, except for a burning blister on my pinky toe. I changed socks twice throughout the walk to prevent blisters, and this actually helped.As I got closer to the bridge, I snapped this great picture.Now I was alongside the Hudson, and the wind was starting to pick up. I didn't see many other people. A severe thunderstorm warning was in effect for the afternoon. I wasn't too worried. I could see the occasional lightning strike across the river in New Jersey. The storm began when I passed by Riverbank State Park. I luckily only had to duck under a highway underpass for 20 minutes to wait the storm out. There were about 10 or so cyclists and fellow walkers taking cover with me.I was feeling pretty good. I had assumed I could fill my water bottle at park fountains, but all had been turned off already for the season.This part of the walk is a blur to me. I passed 130th Street and was at 34th Street before I knew it. I turned inland and stopped at Hudson Yards to get water, use the restroom and get Shake Shack. New York is one of those cool cities where I can stuff my mouth with a chicken sandwich while standing in front of a Dior.I continued and realized how cold it was getting. It reached 45 degrees, and I had to throw on all of my layers. Along the way, I listened to many podcasts, songs, and caught up with friends and family on the phone. One friend even joined me near The Battery for a mile.I reached South Ferry, a good milestone. I rarely take the ferry to Staten Island, but the number of times the bathroom in the ferry terminal has saved me is astronomical at this point. There aren't many public restrooms in Lower Manhattan, especially in the COVID age.I've heard some people describe their marathons or other extreme adventures as it becoming hard to put one foot in front of the other. They have to actively think about physically picking up one foot and moving it past the other. I never reached that point, although my feet definitely felt it. My body was asking, "Why are you doing this? What is the reason?"The rest of the walk was even more of a blur. The second half went by much faster. I hunkered down and just walked. What mildly annoyed me was as I was on my 32nd mile, all I could think about was how if I hadn't taken the wrong turn, I would be done by now.By the time I finished, it was just about 10 p.m. 12 hours later, and I was done. This walk wasn't an emotional experience, like you or even I may have expected. I saw Manhattan and learned that even 36 miles of walking won't break me. While it was insightful, I didn't come away with a life-changing revelation. I didn't stop to take it all in. I jogged to catch the next subway, so I could get home (and into bed) faster.At the end of the walk, my feet felt OK all things considered. I sat down for a few minutes when I got home, the first time I wasn't standing in 12 hours. When I stood up, OH NO, my feet felt awful. They were screaming. The walk four flights up to my bed was agonizing. I slept for 12 hours and felt much better in the morning. It's 48 hours later as I write this, and my feet feel fine (except for a few mild blisters, but I'm used to that as a distance runner).I certainly don't have any regrets, and I'm glad I was able to check this off my bucket list. If this is the kind of thing that excites you, you should walk the perimeter!</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2021: Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/2021</link>
      <description>2021: Year in ReviewDecember 31, 2021AskedMSCHFfor an internship in January by putting a plastic sidewalk newspaper box in front of their office with my resumes inside (the newspaper box even had a permit from city hall). Still working there as the year ends!Ran aduathlonin Central Park (2 mile run, 12 mile bike, 2 mile run).Spent some time working onremote property I boughtfor cheap, clearing a hiking path.Bought a road bike after my hybrid bike was becoming too slow for me.Moved into a co-living house in New York hosted by Edyfi. One of the best decisions of my life. The people and conversations are incredible, and a lot of what I’ve been able to achieve this year has been because of the house. Still living in the house as the year ends!Ran two 1500 meter races at Icahn Stadium two weeks apart. Also YOLO’ed and ran the 2000 meter steeplechase with no hurdle experience (the race with the big hurdles and water pit) and had a lot of fun.My new bike front’s tire got stolen :(Did a lot of odd jobs over the summer, like delivering Uber Eats (not on a bike, while I wasrunning) and taking pictures of properties around NYC (the coolest job was going inside an abandoned GNC and taking photos)Wiped out on my bike in the bike lane. I was OK. Made me realize a) how much I love NYC because people are so nice, and b) I really need to be more careful because it could have been much much worseA video tour of our co-living house went viral on TikTok. Interesting experience seeing how fast something can spread on the internet.Madeoverheard.mewith 5 other friends during a hackathon. The app lets you share funny quotes you overhear your friends saying. We all used it among ourselves for a few months and it was great.Met someone :)Went on vacation with my family to the Outer Banks in North Carolina. Really great spending time with them after not seeing them much during the summer.Had an incredible summer, met so many peopleStarted in-person classes for the first time (my only other year of college was Zoom only)Started on my school’s D3 cross country team, and finally got back into a routine with running. Felt really great to be consistently running with other people.Wrapped up the cross country season by running a 29:45 8kWalked theentire 35 mile perimeterof Manhattan in one dayMy favorite restaurant, where I also worked as a dishwasher for three summers in high school, went out of business. Really savored my last meal thereRan 2 mile races unattached at college indoor track meets. Ran 5:00.7 and 5:00.5. Trying to beat my high school PR of 4:48 by the end of the winter.Interviewedone of the announcers of the New York City subway, Bernie Wagenblast, for a school projectFinished my third semester of collegeIn the span of 24 hours, I left my wallet on a plane, missed a flight, and tested positive for COVID. Spending the New Year's quarantined in a tiny London hotel room :(Will be in NYC again almost all of next year. Looking forward to it!</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2022: Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/2022</link>
      <description>2022: Year in ReviewDecember 31, 2022Rang in the New Year trapped in a London hotel room. I tested positive for COVID after landing in the UK.After London, I took the train by myself to Scotland and stayed in Edinburgh for a few days. Saw sheep in snowy meadows. Could barely understand anyone. Thick Scottish accents are hard to understand at first!Flew to Amsterdam, amid omicron. Amsterdam was completely dead and locked down. I stayed in a 16-bed dorm at a hostel and only one other bed was taken. I went running every morning and took advantage of the city's stunning trail infrastructure. I could take a 20-minute bus ride, and be practically in the middle of nowhere, running past farms, yet still on a paved bike trail. I wish New York was like that.Spent 3 weeks in Dresden, Germany. I lived in Dresden when I was 8, so it was great to reconnect. I stayed in a village outside the city, on a homestead with a family of 5 and their dogs and chickens.I am a huge fan of the transit infrastructure in Germany, and I felt like a kid again riding the Dresden trams to random destinations and watching the train operator through the window behind them. I wanted to grow up to be a tram driver when I was 8 (and still see myself maybe doing that later in life?)One of my favorite things to do while traveling is visiting grocery stores. The upscale, the normal, and the cheap ones. You can learn so much about a culture just by seeing what the average person eats. A grocery store is like a practical museum for food, and the bonus is you get to eat.Flew back to NY in February and went back to Edyfi, the amazing coliving house on the Upper East Side.Relaunched a new version ofRouteshuffle, my website for generating random fitness routes. I completely rewrote and redesigned everything. It's the culmination of almost 5 years of on-and-off research and work. The new routing algorithm generates routes closer to the distance you specify, and prioritizes green space. I know that Routeshuffle will always be a constant in my life, and I love that I can combine my interests in running, maps, and coding to help people move and make money.Flew to Tucson in March to attend OpenStreetMap US'sState of the Mapconference. Much of my work on Routeshuffle depends on OSM, and it was great to connect with like-minded people in the mapping community. Then went to LA for a day. Walked from Santa Monica to LAX because I didn't want to pay for an Uber.Readthis articleabout how in NYC, you can film trucks that illegally idle for 3+ minutes, send it to the government, and claim a quarter of the money the city gets from fining the owner. This is positively impacting the air quality and is lucrative for video submitters. (Shoutout to Mehran for forwarding the article.) I've filmed over 500 videos since then, and sort of stumbled into a micro-culture of other people that use this law. The law also makes for a great discussion about ethics and how extreme laws should be that target climate change.Biked 101 miles (my first century!) from New York to Philadelphia. The whole experience was a blur (as these endurance physical feats usually are for me). Visited my cousin, Justin, at Temple University. Took a scenic route and was in a rural part of New Jersey for a large part of the ride.Took ProfessorTed Widmer's class on climate change innovation in NYC. Myfinal projectvisualized the delivery zones of 15-minute delivery apps in the city, and how they save time, money, and emissions by using e-bikes.Hosted a few Friday night dinners at Edyfi, and cooking for others (and hosting in general) is a gratifying experience.Figured out you can get very close to the Met Gala red carpet by riding a bike down Fifth Avenue in the right lane. Went out with Mayank, Vivian, and Tasha, and pedaled as slowly as we possibly could through the chaos. Got yelled at for biking too slowly.A small group of us living at Edyfi tried to take over and extend the house's lease for three more months through the summer. We ultimately failed, mostly for not communicating with Edyfi's landlord enough and not pushing to sign a lease faster. First-hand learned the lesson that nothing is final until it's on paper and signed.Unable to extend our lease, Edyfi ended in May. Was a bittersweet moment leaving the house. I had lived there for an entire year, by far the longest tenure of any member in the house. I got to live with over 60 talented, friendly, incredible people. Late-night conversations, game nights, impromptu coding collaborations, and plenty of random adventures. Thank you toBenandLukefor creating Edyfi and pushing through the inevitable hurdles that came with managing it. I owe so much of what I have to that house.Spent the summer as a web intern atTendies, working with Jack and Daniel. Learned a lot and was great to be back working in an office every day.Went on 3 different hikes along the Hudson River during the summer with 3 different groups. Will repeat this over and over,Storm Kingis the most beautiful mountain (had the pleasure of biking it last summer and hiking across the river from it this summer)Put up a fake street sign on an unnamed alley and the name I chose is already on Google MapsMoved intoHack Lodgein Brooklyn for a week before classes started back up. With Abhijit and Darren, we builtHopscotch.nyc, a website for finding which neighborhoods to move to in New York. Had the best time living with 20 other college students. Liked the extended hackathon model, and how it was collaborative and not competitive.Moved into Baruch's dorms in Midtown.In October, walked by a weed truck whose big LED displays were in setup mode. Spent 15 minutes reading broken English manuals online to put my own message up (hint) and somehow the sign is still up now (???)Ran for my school's D3 cross-country program. Ran a 28:56 (sub 6 minutes per mile) 8k, and ran at the D3 regionals meet way up in Rochester. In the process of getting an indoor and outdoor track club started at Baruch with Daniel, Julia, and Amy.A GameBoy gameRobertand I developed for MSCHF finally launched, premiering at MSCHF's first solo show at the Perrotin Gallery.BTS In Battlepictures how the boy band BTS may have served their mandatory military service for the South Korean military. Thousands of people attended the opening night. So cool to see people play something I put months of late nights into.Biked over 130 miles in one day, from Midtown Manhattan to Montauk. It was freezing all-day and dark the last few hours, but I've been meaning to check it off my bucket list for several years. Thanks Caleb for joining me!CreatedFast Food Index, a site for comparing the prices of four different fast food chains across the country. Was able to retrieve pricing data by reverse engineering the chains' mobile apps. Got some buzz on Twitter and an article inBusiness Insider.Got called into the dean's office for "fraudulent posting"Started planning what will be, if we're able to pull it off next year, a stunt for the books in NYC.Spent Christmas with family upstate, and flew with them to Lisbon to ring in the new year. Feeling very grateful for everything I have now.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unclaimed property</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/unclaimed-property</link>
      <description>Unclaimed propertyDecember 19, 2023One area that Mehran and I explored in depth last July and decided against pursuing:Let's say you open a bank account and forget about it. Or lose a gift card. Or forget to cash a paycheck. After some period of inactivity, companies are required by law to hand that money over to the state government for you to claim. The many“unclaimed property funds”managed by state governments sum to well over $100 billion. 1 in 7 Americans are owed money, and plenty of businesses are, too. However, governments have little incentive to inform those owed money about this because they makea lotof interest on this cash.This is an information problem. It’s pretty easy to fill out an online form to claim your money, but that’s only helpful if you know that you are owed money. Because if people knew they were owed money, they’d probably collect it, and there are still billions sitting there.Certain states, particularly California, Florida, and Arizona, allow for “bounty hunters” to look through the list of lost funds, contact those on the list, and help them file the paperwork to retrieve their money, assuming they agree. Then the hunters can collect a percentage of the money. There are a good number of individuals who do this for a living, but not many companies, and certainly none that utilize technology to the degree that a startup would.
We cold-called over 100 people who were on the lists and owed at least $1,000. Eventually, we got through to about a third of them, but the premise of hearing “you are owed money and I can help you get it” from a stranger over the phone is not very comforting or believable. No one took us up on the offer. Even then, it’s a cat-and-mouse game. I don’t want to tell them where exactly the money is sitting because if I tell them, they can Google it and get it without me pretty easily. So why would you trust me if I don’t even tell you where the money is?The “file the paperwork for you” is the only straightforward way to be compensated. I just want to solve the information problem! But there’s no straightforward way to be compensated for that.In one experiment, I mailed 30 handwritten notes to random people who were owed money across New York and California. I told them they were owed money by the state, how they could easily claim it themselves, and that if they appreciated the notice, they could send me a “tip.” No responses.So then we turned to businesses. Surely, getting in touch with businesses would be easier, and there might be people in the finance or accounting department interested. We called about 50 businesses of varying sizes in California, that were owed at least $1,000. Getting through phone trees and finding the right department was hard, but then getting past the secretary or screener was even harder. In a few cases, we got through to the right person and they seemed interested! But when we’d send them an email with an agreement ready to sign: crickets. They likely discovered they could file for it themselves.We then talked with several people familiar with the industry. On the individuals side, we were told it was a numbers game, where maybe 1 in 50, or 1 in 100 cold outreaches convert. But it only makes sense to work cases where the person is owed multiple thousands of dollars for the commission to be worth it, and there are a limited number of cases like that. So it doesn’t really scale. And on the business side, the entire industry is built on connections and years of relationships. Which might be possible to scale once you have those relationships? But we were told that each case is wildly different and requires an almost lawyer-like attention to detail to win. In one extreme case, we heard about how a recovery firm found that a defunct LLC was owed a lot of money in unclaimed property. The firm found the owner, who agreed to work with them to get the money back. The firm, out of their own budget, paid a significant amount of unpaid taxes to make the LLC active again. Only then were they able to successfully claim the lost money owed, and both parties took a nice payday home.For those reasons, we gave up on the idea. But I found the problem really interesting. I really hope someone tackles this problem someday. Unfortunately, it seems like something must change at the government level. There’s SO much money sitting there!</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023: Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/2023</link>
      <description>2023: Year in ReviewDecember 31, 2023Every December, I write what I did this year. Nearly every part of my life changed in 2023. I moved to San Francisco in January on a week’s notice. A project I had a hand in turned into more than a project. It was my first year of true “adulting.”This year also marked the first since I was a toddler that I didn’t do any school. But I think it’s fair to say that I learned more this year than any other. My eyes were opened to how much the world has to offer, and the true extent of my agency. While I got answers, I have even more questions! And that’s a good thing, because I need something to do in 2024.Spent New Year’s with my family in Lisbon. Our first family vacation since 2020.Then flew back to my dorm room in Midtown Manhattan.I had January off from college before my last semester, and even then I only had 2 classes left to graduate. So I had decided to start full-time as a frontend engineer at a startup I enjoyed interning at last summer. So it should have been a quiet month.Instead, it was just non-stop. My good friend, Mehran,tweeteda demo of a GPT-3 Google Sheets plugin he made. It went viral and he suddenly had a waitlist of thousands of people. I went straight to his apartment from work every night to help create a product that people could start using.It was exciting! There was real urgency to make something great.  Mehran and I worked until 1 or 2 every night, with conversations about product design, our goals, and AI predictions, along with the inevitable overblown debates about SQL naming conventions and what shade of green is correct.After a few weeks of working well together, we became co-founders and got intoHF0, a 3-month accelerator in San Francisco, led by the incredible Dave, Emily and Evan. On a week’s notice, I decided to quit school and my job, pack up my dorm room, and fly to SF on January 31.San FranciscoHF0 was incredible. We stayed inside of a very large house (might as well be called a building, or a compound, or a military fortress) near Alamo Square, along with the other 18 founders in the program. There were broad ranges of ages, skill sets, beliefs, passions, and personalities, but ambition was a constant.Many times we would need advice about X. Either they’d literally be inside of the house already, or Dave would say “Oh, you should talk to [person very well versed in X],” and we were talking to them within a few hours. After a certain point, you realize that these incredibly helpful conversations are not flukes and are by design. During HF0 and the start of Numerous, I grew so much as a person. It was the first time in my life where I had only one thing to work on. I’ve always had work, school, side projects, sports. It was such a productive environment that just puts you above everything else.In March, we spent the day at the OpenAI office. As we’re getting ready to leave, several people from HF0 start debating whether or not a Bonsai tree in the lobby is real. “These leaves are obviously fake.” “But I feel the soil and it’s moist!” This went on for several minutes. I point out how ironic it is that no one can tell whether a plant is real, all in the lobby of the most important AI company in the world.In May, HF0 ended. Numerous was in a great place. Mehran and I moved out and stayed in SF for the rest of the year, this time living between Twin Peaks and the Castro.That initial feeling of living in a new city is incredible. When your body hasn’t adjusted to the climate like you’re on vacation. When you don’t know the names of any restaurants, streets, or neighborhoods. When you don’t know anyone quite well enough, but friendships are brewing. And when it wanes after a few months, you finally feel at home, but not much in your environment is new. I’ve already burned through that feeling in New York and now San Francisco, arguably the most relevant cities to me in my lifetime.I was against it at first, but went to therapy for a few months after talking withAadil. So much happier in so many ways once I accepted parts of myself.ShenangiansLigma Street: installed a fake street sign in front of Twitter’s headquarters.BratGPT: made a rude parody of ChatGPT. After it got shared around, I sold it for a few hundred bucks to offset API costs.Redirectedseveralabandoneddomain names to funny destinations.Mehran’s Steak House: turned a fake Google Maps listing into a real Manhattan restaurant for one night. 120 diners were under the assumption they were dining at a legitimate 5-star steakhouse.Somehow it came together and worked. So grateful for the 75+ people that helped Mehran,Danielle, and I pull this off. I love my friends. To see them show up (and in most cases, fly out) to help us with a prank… it was just surreal! Everyone stepped up and had fun while doing it. I will truly be smiling about this on my deathbed.The event culminated several months of incredibly fun and chaotic planning. A small sample of what we did: coordinated a complicated rental of a truckload of equipment over the longest email thread you’ve ever seen; fended off a blogger who attempted to ruin the event by running a hit piece days before it happened; went to a wholesale restaurant supply warehouse in Queens to buy $2,000 of food, and got yelled at multiple times for being in the way of feverish employees barreling forklifts down the aisles; worrying the temporary wine permit I applied for wouldn’t be granted (it did a mere 2 days before); found our steak supplier on Reddit and placed an order days before the event (without even tasting the meat because it was too last minute!); buying $10k+ of supplies on our credit cards assuming we’d make all of the money back. We decided last minute to laser etch the menu onto large, circular pieces of wood. Danielle rapidly designed a menu in the most painful Figma document I’ve ever seen. After many hours of failed print jobs, we finally got it looking good. It took 30 minutes for the laser printer to etch each menu, so that meant Mehran stayed overnight inside of a West Village workshop, sleeping in half-hour increments. His alarm kept waking him up to swap out the wood. All of these things tested our friendship. Luckily the three of us made it through without visiting The Vessel.And we loved every single second of it. Who gets to work on projects like this, with other people that care so much? A quote from a diner happened to also encapsulate how I felt: “It’s bullshit. I’m having a great time.”Ex X Chairs: Mehran and I were the winning bidders of some 68 chairs and 68 monitors from a Twitter liquidation auction (why couldn't they have thrown in one more?). We had intended to save money and go to Market Street with friends to move everything out ourselves. But when we called the auction house to coordinate pickup, they bluntly told us we needed to instead hire one of their seemingly expensive moving partners.  We thought we were screwed, but after rereading the auction contract, and several unspoken hints of a lawsuit later, we were able to pick things up ourselves.I drove the largest truck U-Haul offers across SF, to the Twitter office, and back to our apartment, packed with furniture. (And if this story couldn’t get any more haywire, thank you to the FedEx driver who let me off the hook when I stupidly collided with his truck!) We stored everything in our tiny living room, and sold everything within a few days through word-of-mouth. By the grace of God, we more than made up for what we lost on the steakhouse.Ord Phone: For fun one Saturday, I designed mockups of a minimalist black-and-white phone. I thought they looked good, so I wanted to see if there was a market for it. I made a landing page, with a fake checkout to record if anyone tried to actually buy it with their credit card. It didn’t save any actual payment information, though. Several people tried buying it, but the stone cold people of Hacker News doxxed me before it could really gain any traction :(Wanted to sneak intoAPEC in SFand managed to pull it off bypretending to be a journalist.Idling videos: I made a very good amount of money through the NYC government’sclean air bounty program. Last fall, I submitted over 500 videos of trucks illegally idling and finally started receiving checks this summer. Reach out if you live in NY and want to try this. I’m happy to point you in the right direction!During the latter half of the year, Mehran and I shifted to doubling down on growth and putting Numerous into “maintenance mode” in order to spend time in other areas. While Numerous is a profitable and low-overhead business, and there’s a lot of potential in AI, we don’t find that specific idea as interesting anymore. A few things we explored:unclaimed property,a better map with AI,a conversational AI for kids.Visited LA, my grandma in Portland, Josh in Seattle, and went on a road trip. My first time visiting Grand Canyon, Death Valley and a few other national parks. Ran 10 progressively tiring miles in Mammoth Lakes at ~9,000 feet of elevation, which was really nice.As for right now, I’m exploring ideas around local property taxes. Weirdly, it’s very interesting to me, and there are some promising angles. On the fun side, some friends and I are planning an epic scavenger hunt around San Francisco. More to come in the spring :)Visiting Montreal as the year ends with my amazing family. Grateful and excited!Will be in NYC the first week of 2024. Reach out and let’s meet up, old and new friends!</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What a small world</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/small-world</link>
      <description>What a small worldAugust 10, 2024I love asking someone I just met, whose hometown or university or company is the same as a friend, “Do you know ____?” The name game. I am constantly reminded how small the world is. It’s so cool that a friend can be one or two degrees away from another friend, from a completely different part of my life.I assume that this phonemonan is very common, but I only realize it rarely after pulling a loose thread in a conversation.I scraped my Instagram social graph, to find as many of these connections as possible. (I think I keep Instagram more intimate than the average person. My gauge for if I follow someone is “If I saw them at the grocery store, would I stop and talk to them for awhile?”)I got a list of my following and followers pretty easily, usingthis script, and threw out brand accounts. That left 233 people. I labeled where I met each person. Then, I scraped each one of their following lists, for a grand total of 217,723 relationships. I dumped all of this into a SQL database.There’s lots of things I can now do with this data!First, I wanted to visualize all of the relationships between my friends.Each node is a person, and a line between them is a mutual following. Each color signifies where I met that person. As you probably guessed, I am the node in the center.It clumps together pretty naturally! There’s not a whole lot of overlap between my SF/NY, college, and high school friends, but there are a couple nodes (“ambassadors”) who are on the edge of a clump and have connections with lots of colors.Then, I wrote a SQL query to play the name game for me. Specifically, I was looking for accounts that I don’t follow, and that are followed by two of my friends, each friend from a different part of my life.In the results, there were a ton of celebrity and brand accounts, and I neglected to also scrape the follower count, which would have helped me filter that out. So I had to manually go through the data by hand.I found 10 of these relationships! Many of these people went to high school with people from my college, or college with people from my high school. There were a handful of amusing ones, and bear with me, as these are a mouthful:A friend I met on a cycling trip in California went to summer camp in Massacheusetts with a guy who goes to college in upstate New York with my friend who ran cross country with me in high schoolMy childhood next-door neighbor in upstate New York met a girl at a party in Boston, who went to the same high school in Pennsylvania as my San Francisco friendA guy I had many classes with in an upstate New York high school, his college ex-girlfriend’s sister’s high school friend had many college classes with me in New York City</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024: Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://walzr.com/blog/2024</link>
      <description>2024: Year in ReviewDecember 31, 2024Attempted a51 mile walkaround the perimeter of SF. Many friends joined along the way, even for just a mile. I felt like a bus managing a timetable, picking people up and dropping them off. At mile 42, I made the mistake of sitting down for a few minutes, and my muscles tensed up and I legitimately could not walk. I gave up! But successfully retried it later in October, walking from 7 AM to 2 AM. Thanks to Patrick, Theo, and especially Aadil for joining me and the moral support! Because it was painful!!Biked from San Francisco to Los Angeleswith Nate, Elliot, Alex and Cooper. It was just an incredible 10 days. We were along the coast most of the way. I've done plenty of long bike rides, but never any overnight ones. My body was not used to consuming and expending so many calories. Saw a wild tarantula, ate so many meals in small town family-run restaurants, and was overjoyed to end the trip at the Westwood CAVA (why can't CAVA come to SF?!)Jacky created a Socratica node in San Francisco. Every Sunday, a group gets together and works on passion projects for a few hours. It's been a really nice staple in my routine and grateful for the people there.Saw the eclipsein Illinois with a bunch of friends. I usually don’t care that much about natural phenomenons, like landscapes or stars, but this was SO beautiful. I was tearing up. The light seeping out behind the moon. And the energy of everyone in a random field yelling out with joy.Dealt with back pain. It hurt to walk and even lay down in bed for a few months. Really, really bad. Going to my doctor and a chiropractor didn't help. I thought it was pain in my tailbone because of bad posture. After Gytis forced me to talk to Claude in depth about what was going on, we narrowed it down to weak glute muscles, probably from sitting down for way too long at once. Did lots of stretches targeting the glutes and feeling great now!(if you slouch or sit for way too long, STOP! YOU WILL PAY FOR YOUR SINS EVENTUALLY! YOU ARE NEVER TOO YOUNG!)Ran 4x4x24(4 miles, every 4 hours, for 24 hours) with Will, Adi, and others.Pursuit: 15 friends and I made an extremely elaborate, month-long IRL scavenger hunt all over San Francisco. Each of us worked on one of 11 clues. Over a thousand people played at least one clue, and over 200 solved all of them. (And to put it into perspective, each clue took 1-2 hours minimum to solve). It developed sort of a cult following, which was CRAZY! Enormous thanks to Athena, Danielle, Danielle, Theo, Patrick, and SO MANY other friends that graciously created clues, playtested, lent us equipment, gave their time, and the 12 local businesses that let us invade their storefronts. San Francisco is back!!!Ice Spice flag: this culminated from a couple of realizations, with Shreyas and Anton: a) pink American flags with Ice Spice's face on them are mass produced, b) there are lots of empty flagpoles around the city, and c) you can just rent a boom lift for $100.Solo traveled to Japan. My first time in Asia. Didn't really do touristy things and wanted to see what it was like to live there. Walked around for hours in random directions, tried a bunch of restaurants and went intoso many grocery stores.Freeze mob: with Shreyas, re-enactedmy favorite YouTube video, where a mob of people froze in place at the same time for 5 minutes in New York. This time we did it with 100+ people in Golden Gate Park. People got creative with their poses.Bayblade: had the honor of helping Arielle at her spontaneous beyblade tournament. She is aforce. I did the A/V and livestreaming.I can be spotted inthis Daily Show segment. They didn't include anything I said (bruh) but it was really cool to see it finally air. This was taped in NY in 2022 (feels like a lifetime ago).Moved into a wonderful new apartment with great friends.Fast Food Indexrefresh: rebuilt my site for tracking the wildly variable prices of fast food across America. It now updates automatically, and I added a lot more chains.Bop Spotter: mounted an Android phone high up on a pole in the Mission. It's running Shazam 24/7, and picks up songs people blast on the street below. The Washington Postwrote about it.IMG_0001: I readthis blogabout how there are so many unedited, wholesome videos on YouTube with default filenames (like IMG_0001). So I scraped the web and found millions of these kinds of videos, and made a little website to watch them randomly. You really feel every kind of emotion watching them, and the spontaneity of never knowing what you'll see next hooks into natural human curiosity. Somebody called it a "dementia simulator." Astounding that over 600k people used the site the first week it was up. The Washington Post alsowrote about this.Citi Bike scraping: I was scraping the movements of Citi Bikes in New York for a future dataviz project. A few weeks later, the UHC CEO was killed and the police said that the assassin fled on a Citi Bike, so I scrambled to look through my database and find where he maybe went. I tweeted a possible dock he may have gone to (turns out this wasn't right, the police later clarified it wasn't a Citi Bike). The online mob came after me hard! It was very amusing and very frustrating. People joked I looked like the assassin(haha), and other people said I was the assassin(wtf). And The Washington Postwrote about this, too?!Ord: made a novel iOS app that takes advantage of the gyroscopes/accelermeters in AirPods to give you turn-by-turn, spatial walking directions. Instead of hearing "turn left" like you would in Google Maps, you hear an ambient noise on the left side of your head, and the sound changes as you turn. It's really cool to me because it's a lot more passive. It feels like following a friend. My train of thought doesn't get interrupted by the sound. And it's a lot more precise, especially in the woods when you arrive at a 6-way intersection of unnamed trails. This is 95% done and will launch very soon. I got sidetracked with other stuff at the end of the year.Numerous.ai, Mehran and I's startup, is chugging along on autopilot and is now a lifestyle business as of this month. Itching to start something new for the long-term. Not sure what shape that'll take yet. But I'm excited.Writing this on a plane to Europe. Spending Christmas and New Year's with family in Spain. Will be in SF for 2025!</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
